## Oscar Zhou

13 Pigeonwood Lane, Albany, Auckland Central 0211376664 oscarzhou1989@gmail.com http://www.oscarzhou.co.nz

#### **Personal Statement**

I have recently completed my Postgraduate Diploma in Information Science at Massey University. I am looking for an internship or other employment in a company where my skills will make a difference and I can continue my professional development. I am a very fast learner, especially the knowledge and skills related to Computer Science. I worked in China as a C++ developer for one year and a C# developer for two years, working on several commercial projects. Recently, I have been mainly engaged in programing in ASP.NET Framework. In addition to back-end skills, I have mastered some front-end languages, like AngularJS, jQuery, Javascripts. I have a methodical approach to coding and controlling project version.

## **Key Skills**

- Excellent in C++ and C# language and Visual Studio
- An active member of a public speaking association in Auckland
- · A strong affinity and career adaptability
- A fast learner and team worker

## **Project Experience**

### Data analysis of the price of used cars using Python

(September 2016 – October 2016)

### **Project Description:**

Independent python project. To predict the price of used cars in Auckland according to specific vehicle features, such as model, cc, year and kilometres.

Achievements and responsibilities:

The success rate of the prediction reached 90% in small samples and was successfully applied in selecting a cost-effective used car. The project incorporated data scraping, data integration, data wrangling, data visualization and data analysis and coding.

#### **Financial Audit System**

(February 2014 – January 2015)

#### Project Description:

The project involved developing an internal financial audit system, including the management of a large number of contract documents, the preview of audit reports and the classification of business processes.

#### Responsibilities:

Demand analysis, front-end and back-end module added and software maintenance.

## **Medical System**

(August 2013 – January 2015)

#### **Project Description:**

The project involved developing a system for an American medical alliance to share records of the patients' daily drug use for doctors to carry out drug analysis and research.

#### Responsibilities:

Update and maintain the established website with C#, integrate the new platform into the original one.

## **Employment History**

## ASP.NET Developer, Longway Software Development Co.,Ltd, China (August 2013 – August 2015)

I worked 24 months as a web developer with C#. My main job included:

- Writing both front-end and back-end code of a new module with jQuery and C#.
- Updating and maintaining the existing module and function.

# C++ Developer, Tianjin Tiandy Digital Technology Co.,Ltd, China (July 2012 – July 2013)

I worked as a C++ software engineer for one year. The main responsibilities included:

- Updating and maintaining existing Software Development Kit(SDK) with multithreading and socket technology.
- Developing the debugging software for automated testing of the camera circuit board.
- Providing technical support for customers on secondary development based on the SDK.

## **Education**

## **College/School Name**

September 2008 – July 2012 Shenyang Agriculture University (Bachelor Degree) July 2016 – Present Massey University (Postgraudate Diploma, Level 7)